VIVEK YADAV

Phone: +918527372926

Email: vivek.yadav472@gmail.com

Address: Beta 1, Greater Noida, 201308 (IN)

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

JavaScript, Node.js Engineer offering over 6 years of experience. Experience in building top-notch products using JavaScipt and its frameworks. Equipped with the knowledge of modern Node.js stack with Microservices using TypeScript, Docker, Kafka, Redis, TypeORM, MongoDB

EDUCATION

Jun. 2016

B.tech: Electronics and Communication

• ABES Engineering College - Ghaziabad, Uttar Pradesh

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Dec. 2021 – Present Noida, Uttar Pradesh Tech Lead, Sopra Steria

Internally deployed in **Airbus**, managing **data transformations** and currently building **ETL** tool for data transformations, UI based with **drag and drop** that will make it easy for **visualization** and data transformations.

May. 2020 – Dec. 2021 Faridabad, Haryana Backend Developer, Systra India

Building Microservices in Node.js using Typescript, TypeORM, Postgres, Docker, Redis, Kafka.

Following **Hypermedia API** format.

Writing npm libraries.

Nov. 2018 - Apr. 2020 Gurugram, Haryana Software Engineer, Skilrock Technologies Pvt Ltd

To provide all kind of JavaScript solutions.

Worked here on JavaScript (MEAN Stack).

Built the **Channel Management System** using Node.JS and MongoDB which is basically a channel and content management tool to **push real-time data** and results in multiple channels we pre-define.

And built the front-end of the **Retail Management System** in **Angular 6**.

Apr. 2018 - Nov. 2018 New Delhi, Delhi Software Engineer II, Prontus Technologies Pvt Ltd

To make the **Trilyo bot** better than before.

Implemented many new modules.

Worked on Facebook Messenger Bot.

Implemented a lot of features in Trilyo dashboard.

Built bot for concierge using **Dialogflow API** and **Node.js**.

User tracking using Pixel.

Used **MongoDB** for storing user behaviour.

User **Firebase** for image storage and user login

Jul. 2017 - Mar. 2018 New Delhi, Delhi Node.js Developer, Be U Salons

Built Intelligent Notification System with an automatic repeat pattern.

Built **Check-in Check-out module** which tracked operation employees and their visits to various salons and stores.

Built **Trainer Module** which had trainer and trainee section

Built **Customer Care Module** which has various sections through which the customer care executive interacts and this module really helps in understanding customer requirements and their response.

Built **IoT** based **Music Player** which is distributed over all the active salons.

Built **Intelligent Marketing Tool** which can automatically send **SMS**, **Notification**, **Email** to consumers based on the services they have taken and other accumulated data.

Wrote code for various **Admin Reports**.

Oct. 2016 – Jun. 2017 New Delhi, Delhi

Graduate Engineer Trainee, Stonex India Pvt Ltd

Did financial research to accumulate historical data of trading and then crunch data and apply the logic that was told to me by the **CFO** of the organization.

Here I used to **scrape real-time data from NSE and Yahoo finance** to crunch data and bundle monthly data, yearly data, tick data(per second) data and then use them with different logics.

The final result after the implementation of logic was either plotted in the form of graphs using **D3.js** to plot graphs or excel sheets were generated using Node.jS and results were easily **downloadable**.

Calculation modules have over 17 major logics. Technologies I used here were **Node.js Express.js**, **MongoDB**, **Javascript and MySQL**, **D3.js**, **Bootstrap**.

Mar. 2016 – Jun. 2016 Noida, Uttar Pradesh

Software Developer Intern, Saas Labs

Built automation tools using **Pinterest API, Twitter API, Facebook API**, and integrate **Stripe Payment Gateway** on major products.

SKILLS

React Skillful Redis Skillful Angular Skillful TypeORM Experienced Docker Skillful JavasSript Expert Microservices Experienced TypeScript Experienced Node.js Kafka Skillful Expert

SOCIAL LINKS

GitHub : https://github.com/wevek

LinkedIn : https://www.linkedin.com/in/wevek
Twitter : https://twitter.com/vivek_verse
NPM : https://npmjs.com/~wevek